









Leader, problem solver, developer, and designer with over 17 years of experience. I maintain a broad perspective by solving business, organizational, and product problems. I build and maintain systems that increase efficiency such as design systems, code component libraries, onboarding documents/scripts, and standardizing processes. Through user research, competitive analysis, and market research. I can help shape roadmaps by determining the most impactful changes that will meet business KPIs and create a product or service that customers will love.

experience

Hearst Magazines {MAY 2024-PRESENT}

Sr. UX Engineer / Front-end Engineer

- Designed, developed frontend, and conducted user research for a user segmenting tool within 40 days to replace a 3rd party tool that was suddenly being shut down.
- · Building out an internal code component library to replace a library that evolved without clear architectural and code standards.
- · Leading refactor initiative to enforce code standards by properly configuring linting and type checking, and migrating large portions of the codebase to TypeScript.

Blackpoint Cyber {JAN 2022-MAY-2024}

UX Lead - Sr. UX Engineer / Front-end Engineer

- · Led UX design and served as a lead frontend developer for a 2-year project that successfully merged two legacy web apps into a modern React web application
- Named UX lead with responsibility of researching, designing, user testing, frontend development, and interviewing frontend/UI/UX engineering candidates
- · Independently developed an engineer onboarding script and document in my first month, reducing onboarding time from a week to as little as a day
- · Navigated ambiguous requirements and tight deadlines, shaping requirements and collaborating with the team to deliver projects on time
- · Implemented asynchronous processes to streamline communication and feedback across different time zones and countries

Tivity Health {APR 2019-JAN 2022}

Sr. UX Engineer / Front-end Developer

- · Collaboratively developed and designed multiple React projects for Walmart, meeting tight deadlines and adapting to evolving requirements
- · Independently learned Cypress testing library in order to mentor our QA's transition to automated testing
- · Designed and developed component library to increase flexibility and team efficiency
- Mentored colleagues in frontend development and UX design

Phoenix IxDA {NOV 2018-MAR 2020}

Co-organizer

- · Work collaboratively with co-organizers to plan user-experience design focused events
- · Created and delivered a presentation in limited time frame after a speaker dropped out



CVS Health {JULY 2018-APR 2019}

Sr. UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

- Played a key role as the first UX design hire for a new initiative to modernize legacy apps, leading the hiring and mentoring of UX designers
- · Collaboratively designed and developed across multiple products and teams simultaneously
- · Independently created onboarding site in first month that streamlined the onboarding process for hires across multiple offices
- · Created a custom component library and documented it using Storybook

education



{ SEP 2004-DEC 2007 }

Minnesota State **University Moorhead**

Bachelor of Science in **Graphic Communications**

Magna Cum Laude

skills



HTML/JSX CSS / Sass Javascript / TypeScript React / React Native Playwright / Cypress Jest / Vitest Contentful / Sanity / Strapi Accessibility Auth0/Okta Git / GitHub

Design

UI/UX Design User Research **User Testing** Competitive Analysis Market Research A/B & Multivariate Testing Analytics Figma/Sketch/XD Photoshop Illustrator InDesign **Brand Development**



Other

Leadership Mentorship Marketing **SEO** Scrum/Agile/XP











experience

[24]7.ai {JAN 2015-MAY 2018}

UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

- · Successfully collaborated with globally dispersed teams in Sweden and India, designing and developing a React app
- · Responsible for the design process including stakeholder/user interviews, mockups, clickable prototypes, user testing, analytics, and monitoring user recordings
- Team lead for HTML/JSX & CSS development

SyCara Local {DEC 2012-DEC 2014}

UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

- Designed and helped develop a new PHP/Angular web app and custom WordPress site within first year
- · Responsibilities included stakeholder/user interviews, wireframes, mockups, clickable prototypes, user testing, and analytics
- Team lead for HTML & CSS development

Local Motors {JUN 2012—DEC 2012} Web Designer

· Responsibilities included facilitating stakeholder/user interviews, mockups, clickable prototypes, user tests, HTML & CSS/ Sass development, analytics, email newsletters, and print materials

EmpowHER {MAR 2008-MAR 2012} Web Designer

- Promoted within first year and became team lead for HTML & CSS development
- · Responsibilities included mockups, print design, presentations, infographics, and email newsletters
- · Mentored and supervised junior designer and multiple interns

Nerd Cowboy (freelance) { JUN 2005-PRESENT } UX Engineer/Design

• Part-time freelance fullstack development and design services